Register of the Leopold Tyrmand Papers, 1941-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
Leopold Tyrmand Papers
1941-1985
86015
Hoover Institution Archives
25 manuscript boxes, 4 envelopes (10.6 linear feet)
Writings, diaries, correspondence, notes, and printed matter, relating to social conditions in Poland, cultural conditions in communist countries, popular culture in the United States and other Western countries, standards of sexual behavior in the United States, and American conservative thought. Includes fictional writings.
Tyrmand, Leopold
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1920, May 16 Born, Warsaw, Poland
1938-1939 Student, Department of Architecture, L'Academie des Beaux-Arts, Paris
1941 Wilno, Soviet occupied zone, arrested and sentenced for 25 years for political activities
1942-1944 Voluntary labor, Germany
1944 Concentration camp prisoner, Norway
1946 Chief-correspondent, Polish Press Agency, Norway
1946 Returned to Poland
1947-1948 Assumed various positions as journalist
1949-1953 Joined Tygodnik Powszechny
1954 Wrote Dziennik, 1954
1955 Author, Zly
1956 Organized First Jazz Music Festival
1959 Author, Seven Long Voyages
1961 Author, Filip
1964 Suspended from publishing
1965 Traveled around Europe
1966 State Department invitation to U.S.
1967 U.S. permanent residence
1967 Published first essays, New Yorker Magazine
1968-1969 Lecturer, Slavic Literature Department, Columbia University
1970 Author, Notebook of a Dilettante
1970 Editor, Kultura Essays, Explorations in Freedom
1971 Married Mary Ellen Fox
1972 Author, Rosa Luxemburg Contraceptives Cooperative
1976-1980 Associate Director, Rockford College
1977-1985 Editor, Chronicles of Culture
1978 Author, Media Shangri-La
1981 Appointed Vice-President, Rockford College
Edits, Rockford Papers
1985 Author, Ugly, Beautiful People
1985, March, 19 Died, Fort Myers, Florida
American literature.; Civilization, Modern--20th century.; Communism and culture.; Communism.; Conservatism--United States.; Poland--Social conditions.; Poland.; Polish literature.; Polish people--United States.; Sex customs--United States.; United States--Civilization.; United States--Politics and government.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1941-1985 (Box 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Personal documents, identification documents, curricula vitae, notes, correspondence, clippings, brochures, fliers, tickets, business cards, bank statements, invoices, awards, prizes, and other printed matter arranged chronologically by topic or physical form
- DIARIES, 1954-1966 (Box 4-5)
  Notebooks, manuscripts, typescripts, daily occurence books
- NOTES, 1944-1985 (Box 6)
  Manuscripts and typescripts describing retrospective events, literary ideas, thoughts, arranged by physical and topical form
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1948-1985 (Box 7-12)
  Incoming correspondence arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- WRITINGS, 1951-1985 (Box 13-21)
  Drafts and printed copies of articles, reviews, essays, chapters, books, with related correspondence, notes, proofs, contracts, correspondence, and other material, arranged chronologically by date of publication
- SPEECHES AND LECTURES, 1969-1983 (Box 22)
  Drafts and printed copies of speeches, with related notes arranged chronologically by date of presentation
- SUBJECT FILE, 1965-1985 (Box 23-25)
  Notes, notebooks, correspondence, magazines, pamphlets, programs, and other printed matter arranged alphabetically by topic
- NEWSPAPERS, 1967-1984 (Box 25)
  Miscellaneous collection of Polish emigre newspapers
- PHOTOGRAPHS, late 1960's, early 1970's
  General note
  11 photographs / 4 envelopes
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1942-1985
  - General
    - War Period, 1941-1944
      - Ink sketch of Tyrmand's face (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Copies of birth certificates (Folder 2)
      - German Identification Cards, 1941 (Folder 3)
      - School of Architecture certificates, 1942 (Folder 4)
      - German work certificates, 1943-1944 (Folder 5)
      - Certificate of dismissal from German steamship, 1944 (Folder 6)
      - German Provisional Passport, 1943 (Folder 7)
    - Postwar Period, 1945-1956
      - Norwegian certificates, 1945-1946 (Folder 8)
      - Documents issued by Polish Embassy, Denmark, 1946 (Folder 9)
      - Professional Identification Cards, 1947-1950 (Folder 10)
      - Driver's License, 1952 (Folder 11)
      - Press article describing Tyrmand's place of residence and other documents related to his housing situation, 1955-1958 (Folder 12)
      - Certificate of marriage with M.M.Zukowska, 1955 (Folder 13)
    - Poland, 1956-1965
      - Literary contracts, 1957-1961 (Folder 14)
      - Divorce papers, 1958 (Folder 15)
      - Certificate of marriage with B.Hoff, 1959 (Folder 16)
      - Papers related to Tadeusz Hoff incident (Folder 17)
      - Papers related to Tyrmand's stay in Paris, 1963 (Folder 18)
      - Lifetime horoscope, 1963 (Folder 19)
      - Identification issued by Writers Union, 1964 (Folder 20)
      - Invitations to various social and artistic events, mid-60's (Folder 21)
      - Honoraria, 1959-1965 (Folder 22)
      - Work certificates from Tygodnik Powszechny, 1965 (Folder 23)
      - Documents related to European travel, 1965 (Folder 24)
      - Miscellaneous materials connected with trip around Europe, 1965 (Folder 25)
      - Miscelaneous materials connected with trip to Israel (Folder 26)
    - United States, 1966-1975
      - Papers related to State Department Grant trip through U.S., 1966 (Folder 27)
      - Correspondence related to renunciation of property claims, 1966 (Folder 28)
      - Swiss Bank account statements, 1966-1967 (Folder 29)
      - Royalties, 1966-1968 (Folder 30)
      - Application for literary grant, 1966 (Folder 31)
      - Response to job offer, 1966 (Folder 32)
      - Note on personal situation, 1966 (Folder 33)
      - Divorce papers, 1967 (Folder 34)
      - Speech by Machejek denouncing Tyrmand, typescript, 1968 (Folder 35)
      - Letter rebuffing attacks on Tyrmand in Polish press (Folder 36)
      - Documentation related to permanent residence, naturalization, citizenship, 1967-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Invoices and bank statements, 1967 (Folder 2)
      - Identification cards, 1967-1979 (Folder 3)
      - Wedding invitation, 1971 (Folder 4)
      - Typescript on meeting with Rakowski, 1973 (Folder 5)
      - Bank statement, 1974 (Folder 6)
      - Passports, 1974 (Folder 7)
    - Rockford period, 1976-1985
      - Documents related to Tyrmand's first trip to Rockford, 1976 (Folder 8)
      - Drafts of speeches and talks with Rockford officials on future shape of Rockford Institute and related matters, ca. 1977 (Folder 9)
      - Register of Rockford faculty and staff offices, 1976/1977 (Folder 10)
      - Bank statements and certificates, 1981 (Folder 11)
      - Lexicon of Polish Writers, page mentioning Tyrmand, 1981 (Folder 12)
      - Proposal for All American Conservative Conference, ca. 1981 (Folder 13)
      - Tyrmand's notes for conversation with Rockford's President Howard (Folder 14)
      - Propaganda Research Institute, flier on its Advisory Board (Folder 15)
      - Bank statements, 1981-1982 (Folder 16)
      - George Washington Honor Medal, 1981 (Folder 17)
      - Materials on Bohemian Grove Camp, 1981 (Folder 18)
      - Rockford Institute Annual Report, 1984 (Folder 19)
      - Papers related to Governor's Award, 1984 (Folder 20)
      - Papers related to Ingersoll Awards, 1984 (Folder 21)
      - Curriculum Vitae (Folder 22)
      - Tyrmand's account of his career (Folder 23)
      - Condolence letter to Mrs. Tyrmand from President Reagan, 1985 (Folder 24)
  - Publications on Tyrmand
    - Articles
      - Articles from Polish press, 1962-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Articles from Polish emigre press, 1966-1984 (Folder 2)
      - Articles from American press, 1966-1970 (Folder 3)
      - Articles collected post-mortem by W. Wierzewski, 1985 (Folder 4)
      - Interviews, 1966-1981 (Folder 5)
    - Press notes
      - Notes from American press, 1966-1984 (Folder 6)
      - Notes from French, German, Hebrew press, 1967-1968 (Folder 7)
      - Notes from press in Poland, 1968-1984 (Folder 8)
      - Notes from Polish emigre press, 1966-1984 (Folder 9)
- DIARIES, 1954,1966
  - Dziennik 1954
    - Dziennik 1954, 8 notebooks of original manuscripts from (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with N. Karsow concerning publication of diary, 1979-1980 (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Polonia Book Fund, 1978-1981 (Folder 3)
    - Galleys and first printing in Wiadomosci, London, 1973-1979 (Folder 4)
    - Typescripts reflecting 3 stages of editing (Folder 5)
    - First typed copy, (?), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Publishers announcement about forthcoming book, 1980 (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Radio Free Europe concerning broadcast series based on Dziennik 1954, 1980 (Folder 3)
    - Press reviews of Dziennik 1954 in Polish press, 1980 (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence from readers (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with underground publishing house NOWA, concerning possible publication of Dziennik 1954 (Folder 6)
    - Review of NOWA underground edition in Polish underground press (Folder 7)
    - Literary analysis of Dziennik 54 in essay by Roman Zimand, 1954 (Folder 8)
    - Tyrmand's correspondence with Zimand and pastiche of Dziennik as if it were written by Zimand (Folder 9)
  - Diary, 1966
    - Diary from trip around U.S. Holograph, 1966 (Folder 10)
    - "American Diary," New Yorker, Printed copy, November 11, 1967. (Folder 11)
    - Voice of America typescript of broadcast reviewing Tyrmand's "American Diary,", 1967 (Folder 12)
    - "Vision Franca de un Pais. Diario de Viaje por los Estados Unidos," Spanish translation from New Yorker in Comentario, Printed copy, 1968. (Folder 13)
- NOTES, 1944-1985
  - Personal recollections of events, n.d. Typescript, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Notebook with ideas of new books and filmscripts, ca. 1960 (Folder 2)
  - Literary log and notes, Holograph, 1959-1960. (Folder 3)
  - Biographical notes from Holograph, 60's. (Folder 4)
  - Memoir-essay on attempts to obtain passport, n.d. Typescript, 1965 (Folder 5)
  - Notebook kept during trip around Western Europe and to Israel, Holograph, 1965. (Folder 6)
  - Notes as arranged by author and given common title "Memoir", 70's and 80's. Holograph (Folder 7)
  - Notes to "America and I," as arranged by author, Holograph (Folder 8)
  - "America and I," 2 typed copies on Tyrmand's encounter with America, Typescript (Folder 9)
  - Notebook kept in Holograph, 1982. (Folder 10)
  - Notes from "To be in love with America." Holograph, March 1, 1985 (Folder 11)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1946-1985
  - General
    - General
      - Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - 1968-1970
        - A-L (Folder 2)
        - M-Z (Folder 3)
      - 1970-1974 (Folder 4)
    - Family (Folder 5)
    - Literary agents
      - Adler, 1967 (Folder 6)
      - Aison, 1967 (Folder 7)
      - Borchard, 1975 (Folder 8)
      - Brown, 1968-1982 (Folder 9)
      - Caralt, 1965 (Folder 10)
      - Cowles, 1969 (Folder 11)
      - Doubleday, 1971 (Folder 12)
      - Editions du Seuil, 1968 (Folder 13)
      - Fox Chase, 1972-1973 (Folder 14)
      - Geisenheyner and Crone, 1964-1970 (Folder 15)
      - Gyldendal, 1965 (Folder 16)
      - Holbrook, 1971-1972 (Folder 17)
      - Library Press, 1971 (Folder 18)
      - Linder AG, 1969 (Folder 19)
      - Lindley, 1980 (Folder 20)
      - Matson, 1974 (Folder 21)
      - Meredith, 1979 (Folder 22)
      - Russell and Volkening, 1973-1974 (Folder 23)
      - Simon and Schusteri, 1972 (Folder 24)
      - Sterling Lord, 1967-1968 (Folder 25)
      - Strassova, 1978 (Folder 26)
      - WB, 1971 (Folder 27)
      - Viking, 1966 (Folder 28)
    - Newspapers and Magazines
      - Accuracy In Media, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Alternative, 1972 (Folder 2)
      - American Scholar, 1975-1976 (Folder 3)
      - Aneks, 1975 (Folder 4)
      - Art International, 1971 (Folder 5)
      - Atlantic Monthly, 1971-1974 (Folder 6)
      - Battelle, 1972 (Folder 7)
      - Book World, 1969 (Folder 8)
      - CTNYNS, 1970-1973 (Folder 9)
      - Chicago Tribune, 1983 (Folder 10)
      - Commentary, 1967-1974 (Folder 11)
      - Congress Bi-Weekly, 1968 (Folder 12)
      - Contra, 1973 (Folder 13)
      - Dziennik Polski, 1967 (Folder 14)
      - East Europe, 1966 (Folder 15)
      - Ecrits de Paris, 1970 (Folder 16)
      - Encounter, 1971-1972 (Folder 17)
      - Evening Star, 1971 (Folder 18)
      - Esquire, 1966, 1972 (Folder 19)
      - Free Press, 1968-1971 (Folder 20)
      - Harpers, 1973-1984 (Folder 21)
      - Ideas, 1971 (Folder 22)
      - Interplay, 1971 (Folder 23)
      - Mark Twain Journal, 1971 (Folder 24)
      - Merkur, 1969 (Folder 25)
      - Nation, 1968 (Folder 26)
      - National Observer, 1971 (Folder 27)
      - National Review, 1970-1984 (Folder 28)
      - National Zeitung, 1965 (Folder 29)
      - New Criterion, 1982 (Folder 30)
      - New Farm House, n.d. (Folder 31)
      - New Horizon, 1976 (Folder 32)
      - New Leader, 1968 (Folder 33)
      - New Times, 1973 (Folder 34)
      - New York Times, 1968-1974 (Folder 35)
      - New Yorker, 1967-1975 (Folder 36)
      - Nowy Dziennik, 1974-1975 (Folder 37)
      - Playboy, 1971-1972 (Folder 38)
      - Po Prostu, 1975 (Folder 39)
      - Readers Digest, 1971 (Folder 40)
      - Remnant, 1973 (Folder 41)
      - Reporter, 1967-1968 (Folder 42)
      - Saturday Review, 1970-1972 (Folder 43)
      - Seminar, 1974 (Folder 44)
      - Stereo Review, 1970 (Folder 45)
      - Studium, 1976-1980 (Folder 46)
      - Tematy, 1969-1970 (Folder 47)
      - Time, 1970-1975 (Folder 48)
      - Tygodnik Powszechny, 1974 (Folder 49)
      - Wall Street Journal, 1977-1978 (Folder 50)
      - Welt, 1972 (Folder 51)
      - Wiadomosci, 1967-1981 (Folder 52)
      - Zeit, 1965 (Folder 53)
    - Organizations
      - ABC, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - American Association of University Women, 1972 (Folder 2)
      - American Program Bureau, 1966 (Folder 3)
      - American Speakers Bureau, 1972 (Folder 4)
      - Associated Newspapers of Ceylon Limited, 1968 (Folder 5)
      - Authors Guild, 1970 (Folder 6)
      - Cato Institute, 1980 (Folder 7)
      - Centre du Dialogue, 1976 (Folder 8)
      - Church League of America, 1976 (Folder 9)
      - Connecticut Light and Power Company, 1972 (Folder 10)
      - Conservative Book Club, 1976 (Folder 11)
      - Contemporary Authors, n.d. (Folder 12)
      - Ford Foudation, 1967,1970 (Folder 13)
      - Foundation for Economic Education, 1973 (Folder 14)
      - Freedom House, 1973 (Folder 15)
      - Freedom Leadership Foundation, 1971 (Folder 16)
      - Goodson Todman Enterprises, 1967 (Folder 17)
      - John S.Gugenheim Memorial Foundation, 1970-1972 (Folder 18)
      - Institute of International Education, 1970 (Folder 19)
      - Intercollegiate Studies Institute, 1972 (Folder 20)
      - International Telephone and Telegraph, 1972 (Folder 21)
      - Kontinent, 1980, 1983 (Folder 22)
      - Library of Congress, 1968, 1971 (Folder 23)
      - McDowell Colonists, 1970-1971 (Folder 24)
      - Ministerstwo Kultury i Sztuki, 1965 (Folder 25)
      - Mobil, 1970 (Folder 26)
      - Museum of Modern Art, 1970 (Folder 27)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1973-1974 (Folder 28)
      - Newspaper Enterprise Association, 1972 (Folder 29)
      - North American Newspaper Alliance, 1970 (Folder 30)
      - Oesterreichische Gesellschaft fuer Literatur, 1965 (Folder 31)
      - Polish Embassy, Washington, 1966 (Folder 32)
      - Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences, 1967-1974 (Folder 33)
      - Radio Free Europe, 1967-1970 (Folder 34)
      - Republican Town Committee of New Canaan, 1971 (Folder 35)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1966 (Folder 36)
      - Rockford Rotary Club, 1976 (Folder 37)
      - Sage Foudation, 1970 (Folder 38)
      - Soviet Embassy, Warsaw, 1960 (Folder 39)
      - Texas Crude Oil, 1969 (Folder 40)
      - U.S. Department of State, 1968-1972 (Folder 41)
      - United States Industrial Coucil, 1976 (Folder 42)
      - United States Information Agency, 1966-1973 (Folder 43)
      - Zwiazek Polskich Federalistow, 1972 (Folder 44)
    - Publishers
      - Bobbs-Merrill, 1973 (Folder 45)
      - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1968-1970 (Folder 46)
      - Follett, 1972 (Folder 47)
      - Galipan, 1974 (Folder 48)
      - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1973 (Folder 49)
      - Houghton Mifflin, 1969-1973 (Folder 50)
      - Intext, 1972-1973 (Folder 51)
      - Lippincott, 1970 (Folder 52)
      - MIT Press, 1971 (Folder 53)
      - MacMillan, 1967-1983 (Folder 54)
      - Open Court, 1974 (Folder 55)
      - Regnery, 1969-1980 (Folder 56)
      - Schenkman, 1968-1969 (Folder 57)
      - Scribners, 1976-1984 (Folder 58)
      - Simon and Schuster, 1975 (Folder 59)
      - Vanguard, 1969 (Folder 60)
      - Wolff, 1969, 1973 (Folder 61)
    - Universities and colleges
      - Albany, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Albion, 1966 (Folder 2)
      - Ball, 1970 (Folder 3)
      - Canisius, 1970-1971 (Folder 4)
      - College of Europe, 1968 (Folder 5)
      - Columbia, 1968 (Folder 6)
      - Davidson, 1966 (Folder 7)
      - Dickinson, 1970 (Folder 8)
      - Hampshire, 1971 (Folder 9)
      - Harvard, 1966-1969 (Folder 10)
      - Indiana, 1968 (Folder 11)
      - Katolicki Universytet Lubelski, 1983 (Folder 12)
      - Louisiana State, 1980 (Folder 13)
      - Middlebury, 1970-1971 (Folder 14)
      - North Central, 1966 (Folder 15)
      - Princeton, 1966, 1969 (Folder 16)
      - Rice, 1966 (Folder 17)
      - Rockford, 1976-1977 (Folder 18)
      - Stanford, 1967 (Folder 19)
      - University of Florida, 1969 (Folder 20)
      - University of Illinois, Chicago, n.d. (Folder 21)
      - University of North Carolina, 1966 (Folder 22)
      - University of New Mexico, 1972 (Folder 23)
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1968-1969 (Folder 24)
      - University of Toronto, 1968-1969 (Folder 25)
      - Verde Valley, 1968-1970 (Folder 26)
      - Yale, 1966-1967 (Folder 27)
  - Avison, Janus R., 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bell, Daniel, 1977 (Folder 2)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1971 (Folder 3)
  - Bninski, B.N., 1979 (Folder 4)
  - Bruner, Christopher B., n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Brzeski, Andrzej, 1974 (Folder 6)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1968-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Brzozowski, Wojciech, 1981 (Folder 8)
  - Buckley, F., 1984 (Folder 9)
  - Bukiet, Albert, 1974 (Folder 10)
  - Burek, J., 1976 (Folder 11)
  - Byrski, Zbigniew, 1970 (Folder 12)
  - Caldwell, Erskine, 1970 (Folder 13)
  - Carter, Jimmy, 1977 (Folder 14)
  - Chappell, Warren, 1968-1970 (Folder 15)
  - Czajkowski, Henryk, 1972-1975 (Folder 16)
  - Czapski, Jozef, 1967 (Folder 17)
  - Dailidka, Zigmas, 1970 (Folder 18)
  - Dole, Bob, 1984 (Folder 19)
  - Dziwisz, Stanislaw, 1979 (Folder 20)
  - Falange, Dane, 1976 (Folder 21)
  - Fay, Bernard, 1969 (Folder 22)
  - Filipowicz, T., 1976 (Folder 23)
  - Galazka, Jacek M., 1976 (Folder 24)
  - Gella, Alexander, 1970 (Folder 25)
  - Giedroyc, Jerzy
    - 1966 (Folder 26)
    - 1967 (Folder 27)
    - 1968 (Folder 28)
    - 1969 (Folder 29)
    - 1970 (Folder 30)
  - Goerlich, Joachim Georg, 1968 (Folder 31)
  - Gold, Herbert, 1966 (Folder 32)
  - Goldschlag, Fryderyk, n.d. (Folder 33)
  - Gombrowicz, Witold, 1969 (Folder 34)
  - Gomori, George, 1969 (Folder 35)
  - Gorka, J., 1968 (Folder 36)
  - Green, Bob, 1980 (Folder 37)
  - Groszkowski, H., 1969 (Folder 38)
  - Grycz, Wolfgang, 1969 (Folder 39)
  - Grynberg, Henryk, 1970 (Folder 40)
  - Hart, Al, n.d. (Folder 41)
  - Hauptman, Jerzy, 1968-1971 (Folder 42)
  - Hayakawa, S.I., 1977 (Folder 43)
  - Helman, Anatol, 1973 (Folder 44)
  - Helms, Jesse, 1974 (Folder 45)
  - Herbert, Zbigniew, 1970 (Folder 46)
  - Herling-Grudzinski, Gustaw, 1969 (Folder 47)
  - Hoff-Tyrmand, Barbara, 1967 (Folder 48)
  - Howard, John, 1979 (Folder 49)
  - Iwaniuk, W., 1972 (Folder 50)
  - Jelenski, K.A., n.d. (Folder 51)
  - Jordan, David L., 1970 (Folder 52)
  - Juszczak, Albert, 1972 (Folder 53)
  - Kaper, Bronislaw, 1968 (Folder 54)
  - Keith, Joseph, 1978-1979 (Folder 55)
  - Juszczynski, Michal, 1956 (Folder 56)
  - Katzander, Shirley, 1971 (Folder 57)
  - Keene, David A., 1973 (Folder 58)
  - Kemp, Jack, 1984 (Folder 59)
  - Kisielewski, Stefan, 1972-1976 (Folder 60)
  - Kluz, Stan, 1982 (Folder 61)
  - Korbonski, Stefan, 1974 (Folder 62)
  - Kosinski, Jerzy, 1968 (Folder 63)
  - Kowalski, Jan, 1975 (Folder 64)
  - Kozera, Mieczyslaw, 1967 (Folder 65)
  - Krygier, Ryszard, 1971 (Folder 66)
  - Kusielewicz, Eugeniusz, 1976 (Folder 67)
  - Lewis, Flora, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Lichon, Kazimierz, 1960 (Folder 2)
  - Lisiecka, Alicia, 1979 (Folder 3)
  - Lynch, Med, 1984 (Folder 4)
  - Lyons, Eugene, 1968 (Folder 5)
  - Mackiewicz, Jozef, 1967 (Folder 6)
  - Maltby, Richard E., 1979 (Folder 7)
  - Matejko, Aleksander, 1973-1974 (Folder 8)
  - Monseu, Stanislaw, 1972-1973 (Folder 9)
  - Moser, Charles A., 1971-1976 (Folder 10)
  - Mrozek, Slawomir, 1974-1982 (Folder 11)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1981 (Folder 12)
  - Nowotarska, Roza, 1970 (Folder 13)
  - Orzechowski, Witold, 1981 (Folder 14)
  - Pajdak, Marian, 1956 (Folder 15)
  - Piskozub, Zbigniew, 1972 (Folder 16)
  - Podhoretz, John, 1982 (Folder 17)
  - Prelutsky, Burt, 1971 (Folder 18)
  - Pruski, Zbigniew, 1956 (Folder 19)
  - Przyluski, Bronislaw, 1976 (Folder 20)
  - Ramsey, Dang, 1980 (Folder 21)
  - Rhode, Gotthold, 1969-1972 (Folder 22)
  - Robertson, Wilmot, 1982 (Folder 23)
  - Sabbat, Kazimierz, 1968 (Folder 24)
  - Sabbatowa, Hanna, 1968 (Folder 25)
  - Safie, Doris, 1974-1975 (Folder 26)
  - Sakowski, J., 1972-1976 (Folder 27)
  - Salinger, Pierre, 1966 (Folder 28)
  - Seldes, Timothy, 1972 (Folder 29)
  - Skalmowski, W., 1980 (Folder 30)
  - Skolimowski, Henryk, 1969 (Folder 31)
  - Smolinska, Lucyna, 1970 (Folder 32)
  - Spence, John, 1976-1978 (Folder 33)
  - Stadniczenko, Jurij, 1960 (Folder 34)
  - Starczewska, Romualda J., 1970 (Folder 35)
  - Strauss, Bob, 1979 (Folder 36)
  - Szmilichowski, Andrzej, 1980 (Folder 37)
  - Szubska, Barbara, 1970 (Folder 38)
  - Thompson, Ewa M. (Folder 39)
  - Viguerie, Richard A., 1975 (Folder 40)
  - Wadowski, Kazimierz, 1982 (Folder 41)
  - Walsh, Edward J., n.d. (Folder 42)
  - Wandycz, Damian S., 1970 (Folder 43)
  - Weicker, Lowell P., 1973 (Folder 44)
  - Werner, Andrzej, 1980 (Folder 45)
  - Wesoly, Szczepan, 1976 (Folder 46)
  - Wierzewski, Wojciech, 1985 (Folder 47)
  - Williamson, Sam, 1971 (Folder 48)
  - Wittlin, Jozef, 1975 (Folder 49)
  - Wojciechowski, Jerzy A., 1970 (Folder 50)
  - Wozniakowski, Jacek, 1984 (Folder 51)
  - Zablocki, Tadeusz, 1968 (Folder 52)
  - Zawodny, Janusz K., 1976 (Folder 53)
  - Zielinski, Bronislaw, 1957 (Folder 54)
  - Zochowski, Stanislaw, 1970 (Folder 55)
- WRITINGS, 1951-1985
  - Poems (3) written in Frankfurt am Main, Holograph, 1943. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Zly, 1956
    - Reviews
      - Polish, 1956-1981 (Folder 2)
      - British, 1958 (Folder 3)